Jethier Casiano

Junior Front-End Developer



About

A graduate who became very fond of web development. I was curious on how websites and apps were created which has led me to learn the languages of the web and express my creativity.

I am self-taught and have been passionately learning and improving my skills since I started my journey. I would relish the opportunity to utilise and further develop the skills and knowledge that I have learnt.

Projects

kicksmarter - 1st place winner in the Hays & Man City Hackathon 2023. I worked closely with an amazing team to develop and create kicksmarter in a month long hackathon with the main role as the UI Developer. Kicksmarter is an online web-tool which aides coaches with in-game and post-game analysis. I had the opportunity to use my coding skills with React and Sass. Furthermore, I gained some valuable experience working with TypeScript.

Personal Website - I designed and developed my website using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. I applied GSAP to create the animations and also implemented scroll trigger to give it an extra touch. My recent projects can be viewed here.

Education

BSc (Hons) Mathematics, Statistics & Finance 09/2017 - 06/2021 University of Strathclyde, Glasgow

Gained insight on programming languages such as R and Matlab for statistical analysis to find patterns and analyse data.

I've obtained the ability to deal with abstract concepts, break down

The Complete JavaScript Course,
Building Responsive Websites with HTML and CSS

Udemy Academy

problems and present the solutions clearly.

11/2022 - 02/2023

Enrolled in two courses on Udemy totalling up to 106 hours. Along with utilising other online learning platforms such as Codecademy, freeCodeCamp and W3Schools, I was able to learn the fundamentals and advanced concepts of HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Afterwards I created an account on Github and began coding my own projects and continued learning and improving my abilities from there.

Skills

Languages

HTML5, CSS3/Sass, JavaScript/TypeScript

Libraries & Frameworks

React.js , GSAP, Tailwind CSS

Tools & Platform

Git, Github, Figma, Vite

Work Experiences

Bar/Waiting Staff 09/2022-04/2023 The Duchess, Huntingdon

This job has given me a strong organisational skill as well as successfully working well as part of a team with the ability to work long hours in a fast-paced environment.

Front of House/Barista 09/2021-07/2022 Bensons Cafe, Glasgow

Barista 07/2018-09/2018 Loaf Pottery & Coffee Shop, N. Ireland

Interests/Achievements

Music

I have achieved Grade 8 in Musical performance in Piano, and Grade 5 Musical Theory with ABRSM.

Additionally, I was part of a choral ensemble who won the BBC Northern Ireland School Choir of the Year in 2017.

Language Learning

Currently I speak 2 languages fluently, English and Filipino (Tagalog). When I'm not learning to code, I like to take my time in learning Spanish. In the near future, I plan to take the BI DELE exam.